what do you want to cheers
to um
Alabama I put too much in that in the
glass there was a little
much hello today we're going to talk
about Percy Julian one of the greatest
scientists to ever live Percy Julian was
born in Montgomery Alabama in 1899
so that meant he was growing up as a kid
in Jim Crow
segregation land even though it was a
huge obstacle he was able to escape into
plants sounds so dumb what I say it
sounds great he said look at these
plants there's a whole laboratory inside
these things I just want to unlock all
the healing qualities of all these
Plants and Things little Percy decided I
want to be a
scientist he got accepted to depal
University in Indiana he thinks this is
going to be so much different than
Montgomery Alabama and all the
segregation there he gets there black
students are banned from campus uh
living on
campus he finally finds a fraternity
that allows him to live in their
basement in exchange for being their
Butler and they're like can you make us
some hot dogs yeah I guess I'll make you
some hot dogs I'm only trying to be a
scientist here we don't care can you
make us a pizza yeah I'll make a pizza
I'm only and trying to get my goddamn
degree we don't care but at that time in
the United States no
one would allow a black man
to get their
PHD so he goes to Vienna
Austria he's like this place is amazing
I mean we're doing real work here guys
carbons and
hydrogen oxyon and
carrons and that's molecules for you he
writes home and he says this is this
place is amazing and I'm kind of a
badass here like ladies like me that's
all I'm going to say I'll say a little
bit more I've had sex with some people
here and they weren't all racially
racist and stuff I don't want to get
into too much
detail I've penetrated many women all
the best Percy those letters would come
back to haunt him
later no yes Percy's back in America is
like I yeah back I'm from Vienna I got
my PhD no big deal list just keep doing
some science guys says and then his boss
the president at Howard University is
like no no no all those letters that you
wrote about all those babes you were
hooking up with in Vienna this is very
embarrassing to Howard University so
they need you to resign and perc is like
what these were personal
letters and he's like there's a lot of
opportunties
opportunities
you guys I guess he's a man without a
job so he has nowhere to go this guy
William O'Brien who's a vice president
of gliden a paint company he's like this
is absurd this is crazy this guy's a
genius I'm going to hire this guy to be
the director of research in our
laboratory so Percy and his team were
studying soybeans in the lab they're
going this molecule goes to this
molecule and we boom and then we have
this molecule it's going to this
molecule and boom we're having a good
time so he's working on all this
stuff one time Percy's in his lab he
found out there had been an accident and
he was like oh oh some water got into
this 100,000 gallon tank of soybean
juice I'm in trouble and he notices
these crystals on the side of the tub
and he realizes I just made steroids
from a soybean at that time they were
getting steroids from like horse
piss everybody was like whoa Percy just
made progesterone out of a bean he
didn't even have to like use a horse
stick for that there's only so many
horse sticks there is like a million
soybeans uh per every one horse dick
okay Percy starts making millions of
dollars because of this he's able to
help millions of people with things from
arthritis glaucoma birth control and he
was a role model to many other
African-Americans after
him he created so much goddamn stuff I
can't even list all the stuff he created
because there's not enough time on the
show but can I just like
can you just scroll a list of all the
stuff he created yeah we can because
that would be the most efficient way
just while you're talking I can't I
don't have I I
can't but I hope you're seeing the list
of all the stuff you created because
it's insane it's like a lot of
stuff I didn't even know about
that look at
that
h